Guide to the Fales Family Papers MSS.029
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Accretion 2001 B: Series I, Fales Family
  - Samuel Fales Dunlap's suit against family (Barstow, Dunlap): ca. 1857 (Box 38, Folder 150)
  - trust fund for Augusta Fales (Mrs. Andrew) Dunlap, undated (Box 38, Folder 151)
  - Augusta (L. A. C. A. ) Fales Dunlap: estate, accounts, receipts, ca. 1850's (Box 38, Folder 152)
  - Augusta Dunlap: inventory (n. d.), undated (Box 38, Folder 153)
  - Dunlap coat-of-arms: notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 154)
  - calling cards left for Samuel Fales Dunlap, undated (Box 38, Folder 155)
  - will of Sarah Dunlap: 1839 (Box 38, Folder 156)
  - litigation: Andrew Dunlap, ca. 1830's (Box 38, Folder 157)
  - litigation: Andrew Dunlap, prosecuting attorney (?), 1834 (Box 38, Folder 158)
  - litigation: incl. Charges against Joachim Antonio ca. 1830's (Box 38, Folder 159)
  - reburial of Haliburton Fales (d. 1839?) (Box 38, Folder 160)
  - shares in oil companies: ca. 1864-71, 1864-1871 (Box 38, Folder 161)
  - Boston: notebook with "Names of Friends", undated (Box 38, Folder 162)
  - dinner menu: Jan 14 1885 (Box 38, Folder 163)
  - 19th century documents: unidentified, undated (Box 38, Folder 164)
  - hair of Susan Maria Fales (1809-1853) (Box 39, Folder 165)
  - photos: unidentified, undated (Box 39, Folder 166)
  - photos: Aunt Winifred Robb / Lucy Mitchell (?), undated (Box 39, Folder 167)
  - photos: Iselin / Sibley, undated (Box 39, Folder 168)
  - photos: family friends, undated (Box 39, Folder 169)
  - photos: "Uncle Sam Fales" (1848-1892) (Box 39, Folder 170)
  - photos: Beale, undated (Box 39, Folder 171)
  - photos: Haliburton Fales (1849-1929); Margaret Corse Fales (wife); other Corse family (Box 39, Folder 172)
  - photos: Tremont St., undated (Box 39, Folder 173)
  - photos: Dunlap, undated (Box 39, Folder 174)
  - photos: John B. Mills, undated (Box 39, Folder 175)
  - photos: Leonard Jerome, undated (Box 39, Folder 176)
  - photos: Kate Sixsmith (Hal Bridgham's nurse), undated (Box 39, Folder 177)
  - photos: William Henry Law (2nd husband of Mrs. H. Fales' sister), undated (Box 39, Folder 178)
  - photos: Jenny Lind, opera singer, undated (Box 39, Folder 179)
  - photos: Haliburton Fales, undated (Box 39, Folder 180)
  - photos: various 19th c. ladies, undated (Box 39, Folder 181)
  - photos: 2 miniature tintypes (unidentified), undated (Box 39, Folder 182)
  - photos: Samuel Fales of Boston (1775-1848); Abigail Haliburton (wife; 1773-1839) (Box 39, Folder 183)
  - photos: Samuel Bradford Fales of Philadelphia (1804-1880) (Box 39, Folder 184)
  - photos: Haliburton Fales of Boston (1815-1869) (Box 39, Folder 185)
  - photos: DeCoursey Fales Sr., undated (Box 39, Folder 186)
  - photos: DeCoursey Fales Sr., undated (Box 39, Folder 187)
  - photos: Fales' yacht, "Nina", undated (Box 39, Folder 188)
  - photos: various Fales, Mitchell, Look, Brock, & Higginson children, ca. 1930 (Box 39, Folder 189)
  - photos: Hal Fales I, undated (Box 39, Folder 190)
  - photos: Hal Fales III (ca. 1930's?), 1930-1940 (Box 39, Folder 191)
  - photos: Sam Fales (ca. 1920's), 1920-1930 (Box 39, Folder 192)
  - photos: Clara Huntington, undated (Box 39, Folder 193)
  - photos: Fanny Schermerhorn Bridgham, undated (Box 39, Folder 194)
  - photos: "Fraulein", undated (Box 39, Folder 195)
  - photos: Cornell, undated (Box 39, Folder 196)
  - photos: Hal Fales (1873) (Box 39, Folder 197)
  - photos: Nancy Fales (1955 or 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 39, Folder 198)
  - photos: Clarence Van Schaik Mitchell / Clarence P. Mitchell, undated (Box 39, Folder 199)
  - photos: DeCoursey Fales Jr. -1964 (Box 39, Folder 200)
  - photos: Mitchell, incl. Dorothy Mitchell Fales, undated (Box 39, Folder 201)
  - photos: Sandra Fales Hillman (ca. 1952-1958) (Box 39, Folder 202)
  - photos: various houses & sites, undated (Box 39, Folder 203)
  - photos: DeCoursey Fales Sr., undated (Box 39, Folder 204)
  - photos: Thomas & James Higginson (1924) (Box 39, Folder 205)
  - photos: Brock, undated (Box 39, Folder 206)
  - photos: "Mummy of Sethos"; President McKinley delivering a speech ca. 1900 (Box 39, Folder 206A.)
  - Illustrated Almanac, 1873 and "Tousey & Small's Boys Monthly" (n. d. ) (Box 39, Folder 207)
  - New York Herald (pages): Feb 18 1850; Nov 20 1851, 1850, 1851 (Box 39A, Folder 208)
  - Oversize photos: Elizabeth Fales Fowler; Pennbrook family gathering (1930); Mitchell Portraits; Samuel B. Fales (Box 39A, Folder 209)
  - Oversize photos: DeCoursey Fales Sr. on horseback; Clarence V. S. Mitchell; Mary Tyler Brock; dinner @ Union Club (1930); Ellen Fales Lomasney; DeCoursey Fales Sr. -1930 (Box 39A, Folder 210)
  - Grant, Gordon and Harold Platt. Ship Ahoy! A Construction Book for Fireside Sailors. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, Doran, & Co., 1934. (Box 39A, Folder 211)
  - Burton, Leslie. Children Here, Children There: Changing Picture Books. Bronx, NY: Child Guidance Products (n. d.), undated (Box 40, Folder 212)
  - Ford, Lauren. The Little Book About God. New York: Doubleday, Doran, & Co., 1939. (Box 40, Folder 213)
  - Hugo, Victor. Les Miserables. Trans. Charles E. Wilbour. New York: A. L. Burt Co. (n. d.). [copy belonging to "DeCoursey Fales, Esq., of the USS Seattle"], undated (Box 40, Folder 214)
  - McCormick, Paul, et. Al., eds. Adventures in English Literature. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1973. [inscribed in front by "Susan Marya Fales"] (Box 40, Folder 215)
  - Navy Department, United States of America. Regulations for the Government of the Navy of the United States (Navy Regulations). Washington: Government Printing Office, 1913. (Box 40, Folder 216)
  - Roberts, Paul. The Roberts English Series: A Linguistics Program. Book 4. New York: Harcourt, Brace, & World, Inc., 1966. (Box 40, Folder 217)
  - Scrapbook: 19th century photo scrapbook, incl. portrait photos, drawings of ladies & various sporting, leisure, & domestic scenes, drawings & photos of ladies in undergarments (pin-up girls?), undated (Box 40, Folder 218)
  - Scrapbook (19thc ?): fine art postcards, undated (Box 41, Folder 219)
  - Scrapbook (19thc ?): fine art postcards, undated (Box 42, Folder 220)
  - Scrapbook (19thc ?): fine art postcards, undated (Box 42, Folder 220A.)
  - Scrapbook (19thc ?): fine art postcards, undated (Box 43, Folder 221)
- Accretion 2003: Series VI, Lyman Law
  Scope and Content
  This accretion consists of legal contracts, commissions, and receipts relating to Lyman Law's legal practice in early 19th century New London, Connecticut. Also included are Lyman Law's personal letters to his son, William Henry Law, as well as documents relating to William Henry Law's legal practice. There are two fine daguerreotype portraits listed at the end of this series.
  Biographical/Historical note
  William Henry Law was the second husband of Harriet Beale; Beale was an older sister of Elizabeth Jane Beale, the wife of Haliburton Fales.
  - Letter - Unknown to Lyman Law, March 4, 1794 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Lyman Law receipts, 1795-1832 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - William H. Law receipts, 1810-1811 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Lyman Law to William H. Law, 1811-1813 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - William H. Law - Record Book, 1834-1836 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - William H. Law Commission (found in Notary Record Book between Jun. 26 & Jun. 3, 1835 entries) (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Contracts, 1837-1841 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - receipts, 1837 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - J.B. McCall Correspondence, 1838-1839 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - receipts, 1838 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - receipts, January 1839 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - receipts, February 1839 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - receipts, March 1839 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - receipts, April 1839 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - receipts, May 1839 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - receipts, June 1839 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - receipts, July 1839 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - receipts, August 1839 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - receipts, September 1839 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - receipts, October 1839 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - receipts, December 1839 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - receipts, 1840 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Lyman Law - Checks and Checkbook (Bound Together), 1841-1842 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - receipts, 1841 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - receipts, 1842 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Wabash Canal - Petition and Division of Commission of Prints, 1845 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - William J. Mills Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Song Book, undated (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Fragment found in William H. Law's Record Book, undated [found between entries for Feb. 15, 1855 & Mar. 17, 1855] (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - receipts (Bound Together), undated (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Two Daguerreotpye portraits, circa 1850 (Box 46)
  - Oversize Accretion 2003, Series VI, Lyman Law
    - Lyman Law - Commissions, 1793-1838 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Lyman Law to William H. Law, 1811-1813 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - William H. Law Correspondence, 1820 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - J. Dodge Correspondence, 1832-1833 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Judge Samuel Hall to James B. McCall, 1835-1838 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Contracts, 1837-1839 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Receipts, 1839-1840 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Fragment of Woodcut [found in front cover of William H. Law's Record Book], undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Sermon, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
- [Man on a Horse], Undated; cuid6204; 1 item one painting (Box Shared Fales 011, Folder 4)
  Paintings (visual works)
- [Sir Walter Scott] ?, undated; MSS.029.cuid21318 (Item MSS.029.cuid21318)
- Portrait of Haliburton Fales, 1911; MSS.029.cuid21370 (Item MSS.029.cuid21370)
- William Thackeray, undated; MSS.029.cuid21371 (Item MSS.029.cuid21371)